Furkan Tunalı Résumé

Summary

I'm a full stack web developer* and multidisciplinary designer*

.

Info

Fullname: Mustafa Furkan Tunalı

Available working permits: 4 years of Blue Card EU Residential and Working Permit holder and Turkish Citizenship

Current residency: Berlin

Marital status: Single

Contact

• Web: FurkanTunali.com

• E-mail: mail@furkantunali.com

• Phone: +49 174 6492854

• <u>LinkedIn</u>

• GitHub

Experiences

• Universal JavaScript Engineer at Pixsy GmbH, Berlin

01/2017 - 08/2017

My responsibilities were:

- Delivering new features on both ends with using JavaScript.
- Delivering code with unit, integration and E2E covered tests.
- Maintaining or migrating existing features.
- Developing micro-services.
- Improving our architecture and stack when it's possible.
- Integrating and maintaining data on Mongo, Stripe and SalesForce.
- Keeping an eye on app health with Heroku and Sentry reports.
- Following KANBAN with some Agile methods.
- Reviewing codes from our team's pull requests.
- Following our code conventions and guidelines.

Some of the technology and services that I used:

- Node, Lambda/Serverless, React, Redux, FlowType, AWS, WebPack, Webpack Isomorphic Tools, Koa, MongoDB, Babel, HighlandJS, SalesForce API, Mixpanel, Mocha, Chai, Yadda, Webdriver.io on top of Selenium, Stripe API, Sentry, Github
- Software Architect and JavaScript Developer at <u>Talented</u>
 <u>Square, CA</u>

08/2015 - 08/2016

Some of the projects:

 Front-end development for a giant multinational retail corporation's online wholesale seller portal which I cannot disclose it's name but feel free to contact for the details.

Some of the project skills: JavaScript, Angular, AMD, Gulp, CSS, SCSS, HTML and small of amount of Maven and Jetty.

 Performance and architectural improvements and JavaScript development to an e-commerce website to same company described above.

Some of the project skills: Browser and mobile optimization, JavaScript, Backbone, AMD, CSS, jQuery, HTML and Ant.

 Architectural design and javascript development for a new recruiting startup project.

Some of the project skills: architectural decisions, JavaScript, LoopBack, Webpack, Gulp, MySql, React, Redux, HTML, SCSS.

 Founder, full stack web developer and designer at NOD studios, Istanbul

11/2012 - 07/2015

Some of the projects:

• Web development and design for Gym & Tonic

Some of the project skills: Design, JavaScript, PHP, HTML, LESS, CSS, CanJS, Mustache.

• Web development for <u>Silent + Blessed</u>

Some of the project skills: Design, JavaScript, HTML, LESS, CSS, CanJS, Mustache.

Web development and design for <u>Mirjam Schmitt</u>

Some of the project skills: Design, JavaScript, HTML, LESS, CSS, CanJS, Mustache, Wordpress, Worpress JSON API.

Web development and design and UX consultancy for <u>Les</u>
 <u>Benjamins</u>

Some of the project skills: Wireframing, Mockup, Design, JavaScript, HTML, LESS, CSS, CanJS, Mustache, CakePHP.

Web development, design, mobile app design, UX design and

refactoring legacy code for etiqadd

Some of the project skills: Wireframing, Design, JavaScript, AMD, PHP, Codelgniter

Social web app design and gamification for <u>Gripati</u>

Some of the project skills: Wireframing, Design, JavaScript, AMD, PHP, Codelgniter

Front-end mobile web development for <u>LigTV</u>

Some of the project skills: Mobile optimization, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Internal web site design and full stack web development for <u>Ülker</u>

Some of the project skills: PHP, CakePHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

 Server side web RSS aggregator API development for a mobile app of MB Apps

Some of the project skills: CakePHP, PHP

Full stack web development for <u>Umut Üzümleri</u> movie

Some of the project skills: Design, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

- Open source projects and libraries at <u>Github</u>
- Full stack web developer at FOX International Channels,
 Istanbul

01/2012 - 12/2012

Development of some social app and microsite web development for some clients including:

<u>Samsung Turkey</u>, <u>National Geographic Turkey</u>, <u>Nokia Turkey</u>, <u>True Blood TV show</u>, <u>Glee TV Show</u>, <u>TerraNova TV show</u>

• Front-end developer and designer at projectz, Istanbul

06/2011 - 12/2011

Front-end coding, refactoring and web design for startup project <u>yardimlazim.com</u>

• Full stack developer at Manajans / JWT, Istanbul

05/2009 - 06/2011

Development of web sites, CMS development, online communities, social apps and microsites for some clients including:

Miller, GncTurkcell / Turkcell, Eston, First, Bomonti, Efes, TeraBrokers (Formerly TeraMenkul)

Front-end developer at <u>Tribal DDB Worldwide</u>
 <u>Istanbul(formerly Manadigital)</u>

03/2009 - 05/2009

Front-end development for some clients including:

patlican / avea, TTNET

Full stack developer at <u>Ping Digital Agency Istanbul(formerly OnKaplan)</u>

05/2008 - 03/2009

Garanti, TTNET

Designer, front-end developer and flash developer at Koçak
 Dizayn, Istanbul

05/2008 - 03/2009

Design, concept art creation, front-end development and illustration for

an online art community startup.

• Designer, front-end developer at MedyaNova, Istanbul

05/2005 - 02/2007

Design and front-end web development for various web projects mostly travel, hotel and hotel franchise clients like <u>Best Western Hotels</u>.

• Internship at MedyaNova, Istanbul

04/2005 - 05/2005

Skills

- Programming & Development
 - Software & Markup Languages
 - JavaScript / ECMAScript,
 EcmaScript 2016 / ES6,
 EcmaScript 2017 / ES7 advanced
 - Node.js advanced
 - PHP advanced
 - <u>HTML</u> / <u>HTML5</u> / <u>xHTML</u> advanced
 - CSS / CSS3, less, SASS / SCSS advanced
 - Python beginner
 - Ruby beginner
 - <u>SQL</u> advanced
 - Familiar patterns / conventions: FP, Isomorphic / Universal Javascript, TDD, BDD, MVC, MVVM, OOP, Prototypal OOP, OLOO, AOP, ES6 Modules, AMD, CommonJS, Semantic Versioning
 - Other: Bash, ASP, .NET, C, C++, PIC
 - Tools

Some of the frameworks

- RxJS (beginner)
- Serverless for Lambda (advanced)
- <u>Koa</u> (intermediate)
- React (advanced)
- Redux (advanced)
- Flux (intermediate)
- Angular (advanced)
- Backbone (advanced)
- CanJS (advanced)
- polymer (intermediate)
- Aurelia (beginner)
- express (intermediate)
- LoopBack (advanced)
- CakePHP (advanced)
- <u>lithium</u> (intermediate)
- Codelgniter (intermediate)

Databases

- RethinkDB beginner
- MongoDB advanced
- MySQL advanced
- <u>SQLite</u> advanced

Libraries and Miscellaneous Tools

Flow Type, Atom, npm, Homebrew, Babel, gulp, Jest, Chai Assertion Library, webpack, HighlandJS, WebStorm, Protractor, jQuery, RequireJS, Underscore.js / lodash, git, PM2, Wordpress, IBM API Connect, Bower, SystemJS, jspm, composer, pip, gem, Apache Http Server, PhoneGap, appcelerator, fish, Bash

APIs and Services

Heroku, AWS (Amazon Web Services), SalesForce, Stripe, Mixpanel, Facebook, Twitter, Shopify, Flickr, Tumblr, WP REST API, SoundCloud, Pinterest

Operating Systems

OS X, Ubuntu, Windows (Using it for playing some video games)

• Design

- Web Design on web browser
- UI Design
- Wireframing / Mockup Design
- Responsive Design
- UI Design
- Web UX
- Branding / Identity
- Print Design

Tools

- Adobe Photoshop advanced
- Sketch beginner
- Adobe Illustrator advanced
- Adobe Fireworks intermediate

Languages

- Turkish native
- English advanced

Education

Computer Programming and Technology at <u>Kadir Has</u>
 <u>University</u>

Sehremini Anadolu High School

Interests

- DJ and Founder at AmbientData
- Open source
- Experimenting with side-projects
- Sci-Fi books, movies etc.
- Typography
- Photo manipulation
- Travelling
- Home brewing coffee and beer
- Video games
- Any kind of nerd activity